# **Alexandre TANGUY**

#### **Engineering manager**

Leader of IT technical teams and projects with a network and security engineer background. I am not a software engineer.







## ■ Who am I and what am I looking for?

After 8 years in the tech field, as a network and security engineer, where I learned lots of things and grow up as an engineer and a human being, I understood that I was happier leading a team and helping them to achieve big projects and grow in their skills. Moreover...

### ■ Professional experience

Engineering Manager @ OVHcloud (January 2020 - Present)

Team leader of the Network Data squad, composed of the Network Observability and the Network IPAM teams.

- Point of contact for other teams and PU, for Network observability and IP related topics
- Follow-up on projects
- Creation of roadmaps with Program managers support
- Agile methodology implementation and animation: sprint planning, daily, sprint review, retrospectives, etc.

Network Engineer @ OVHcloud (Mars 2018 - January 2020)

Member of the Network Design Datacenter team, I was in charge of the vRack product design and projects.

- In charge of the design of network products
- In charge of R&D on some projects
- Technologies: BGP, VXLAN, ECMP, Cisco and Arista devices

**Network and Security Engineer** @ Cdiscount (January 2016 - Mars 2018)

Member of the Security team for 1 year and then the SRE team for 1 year (internal move-up).

- In charge of
- In charge of
- *Technologies:* Cisco ACI, Checkpoint firewalls, F5 loadbalancers

# ■ Education and languages

TBC

#### Activities and interests

- Hobbies: reading (a lot!),
- **Sports**: climbing/bouldering, running, cycling.

Volunteering